<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//Novell//DTD NovDoc XML V1.0//EN" "novdocx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % NOVDOC.DEACTIVATE.IDREF "INCLUDE">
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
  %entities;
]>

<chapter id="cha-tuning-linuxrc">
 <title>Linuxrc</title>
 <para></para>
 <sect1>
  <title>Foo</title>
  <para></para>
 </sect1>
 <!--

lynx -dump http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc

Linuxrc

   linuxrc is a small program that runs before the actual installation
   program [38]YaST is started.

   It is responsible for the hardware setup and will search for an
   installation repository. To specify the repository location, use the
   [39]install option.

   The use of linuxrc is not limited to the installation. You can also use
   it as a boot tool for an installed system and even for an independent
   RAM disk–based rescue system.

   Linuxrc writes its settings to a special file [40]/etc/install.inf that
   makes them easy-to-read later. See the reference page [41]here.

Contents

     * [42]1 Passing parameters
     * [43]2 Parameter Reference
     * [44]3 Special parameters for S/390 and zSeries
     * [45]4 Special parameters not handled by Linuxrc itself
     * [46]5 Errata
          + [47]5.1 openSUSE 10.3

Passing parameters

   linuxrc accepts parameters either by command line or through
   configuration files. For this, pass the file location using the
   [48]info parameter. You can use this option several times - linuxrc
   will read all files.

   linuxrc parameters are case-insensitive and you can add as many
   hyphens, underscores, or dots as you want.

   The option argument can be put in doublequotes.

   For example, the following are all equivalent:
SSHPassword=foo
sshpassword="foo"
ssh.password=foo
ssh-password="foo"
ssh_password=foo
S.Shp-AsSw._.orD=foo

   Parameters that are unknown to linuxrc but are of the form foo.bar are
   interpreted as options to kernel modules. See [49]options for details.

Parameter Reference

   Some parameters expect a URL as argument. Here is a short overview of
   the syntax.

   Supported schemes:
cd (or cdrom)         # CD-ROM
hd (or hard disk)      # local hard disk
disk                  # any local disk device (CD-ROM, hard disk or floppy)
file                  # local file
floppy                # floppy (better use disk)
ftp                   # ftp server
http                  # http server
nfs                   # nfs server
slp                   # use SLP to get the real URL
smb (or cifs)         # Windows share
tftp                  # TFTP server

   General format:
scheme://domain;user:password@server:port/path?query

   If scheme: is missing, a relative URL is assumed which is normally
   relative to the repository.

   Don't forget the brackets if you enter a literal IPv6 address; e.g.:
http://[2001:db8:42:815::1]/some_dir

   For smb/cifs path is preceded with the share name:
path = share/path

   domain is only for scheme smb/cifs and specifies the domain/workgroup
   of the user.

   For references to local devices, using cd, disk, floppy, hd, path can
   optionally be preceded with the device name
 path = device/path

   For another way to specify the device, see below.

   query may be one or more of
device=device_pattern
instsys=URL             # install parameter only
service=slp_service     # slp scheme only
descr=slp_descr         # slp scheme only
url=slp_url             # slp scheme only

   separated by '&'.

   device specifies the device to use (linuxrc will normally try all
   devices in turn). You can use typical shell metacharacters here. Like:
install=cd:/?device=sr0                  # first CD-ROM
install=cd:/sr0                          # alternative form
install=cd:/dev/sr0                      # optionally add /dev
install=hd:/?device=sdb*                 # any partition on 2nd hard disk
install=hd:/?device=*label/foo           # partition with fs label 'foo'
install=nfs://foo/bar?device=eth0        # works with network devices, too
install=nfs://foo/bar?device=00:0e:0c:*  # matches MAC addresses, too

   instsys is only relevant for the [50]install parameter. Also, see
   [51]instsys option.

   service, descr and url are only useful for scheme slp and limit the
   list of URLs. Like:
# get URL list via SLP
install=slp:/
# ... but only those with 'openSUSE' in the description
install=slp:/?descr=*openSUSE*
# ... and only ftp URLs
install=slp:/?descr=*openSUSE*&url=ftp:*

   You will probably never need any parameter except [52]install. But in
   case you do, here is the complete list.

      Parameter    Description
   AddSwap

   Tries to activate a swap partition. If set to 0, the system does not
   try to activate a swap partition. If set to a positive number, the
   partition corresponding to the number is activated as a swap partition.
   With a negative number, linuxrc will present you a dialog for selecting
   the swap partition or creating a swap file. Alternatively, specify the
   full device name of a partition.

   Examples:
 addswap=/dev/sda2
 # '/dev/' is optional
 addswap=sda2
 # 5th swap partition
 addswap=5
 # never ask for swap (even if it might be a good idea)
 addswap=0
 # interactive
 addswap=-1

   Alias

   AutoYaST

   This parameter can be used to initiate an automatic installation using
   [53]AutoYaST. The value must be a URL pointing to an AutoYaST
   installation profile. See parameter Installation for all possible
   formats. In some cases is good idea add also option netsetup=dhcp
 Example:
 AutoYast=[54]ftp://autoyast_profile.xml

   BootDisk

   BootFile

   BOOTPTimeout

   Timeout for BOOTP requests in seconds.
   Bootpwait

   Sets a delay between interface setup and bootp request in seconds.

   Example:
 BootpWait=10

   Broadcast

   Broadcast IP address
 Example:
 Broadcast=10.10.255.255

   BrokenModules

   Comma-separated list of modules that will not be loaded during
   initialization.

   Note that it does not work cumulative. If you use this option several
   times, the last one will win. This allows you, for example, to clear
   this list in a driver update.

   Example:
BrokenModules=ahci,ata_piix

   CDROMDevice

   No longer supported. Use [55]device or [56]install.
   ConsoleDevice

   Console device name.
 Example:
 ConsoleDevice=/dev/tty9

   Device

   Specify the storage device to use when looking for a repository. See
   [57]device description for allowed values.

   Normally, this is not necessary. But if you really need this option,
   consider adding it to the URL of the [58]Install parameter.

   Examples:
device=sr1        # 2nd CD-ROM drive
device=sdc*       # partition on 3rd disk

   Display

   windowed only

   Sets the linuxrc color scheme.
     * 1 - Monochromatic display [black/white]
     * 2 - VGA colors [blue/white] (default)
     * 3 - Alternative VGA colors [green/white]

   Examples:
Display=3   # go greenish

   Display_IP

   IP address of X server for remote installation via X11
 Example:
 Display_IP=10.10.1.57

   DHCP

   No longer supported.
   DHCPCD

   Additional options for dhcpcd (the DHCP client used by linuxrc).

   Example:
dhcpcd=-B

   DHCPTimeout

   Timeout for DHCP requests in seconds.

   Example:
dhcptimeout=120

   Domain

   Domain search path for DNS. Only useful for non-DHCP network config.

   Example:
domain=opensuse.org

   DoSCSIRename

   Reorder SCSI devices so that USB and Firewire devices come last. And do
   it NOW (that is, when the option is parsed).

   Don't use this option.

   Example:
doscsirename=1

   DriverUpdate

   Please use [59]dud instead.

   For documentation on driver updates see
   [60]http://ftp.suse.com/pub/people/hvogel/Update-Media-HOWTO/index.html
   .

   There are two semantics: driverupdate=1 and driverupdate=<url>. With
   driverupdate=1 linuxrc lets you interactively select a driverupdate.
   driverupdate=<url> specifies the location of the driver update
   directly. <url> should point either to a directory with the unpacked
   driver update or to a driver update archive.

   You can use this option several times; linuxrc will load all specified
   updates.

   For supported schemes and a syntax description, look [61]here.

   Note that driver updates are automatically searched for on your
   installation server/media. You don't have to use this option for that.

   Examples:
# ask for driver update disk
driverupdate=1
# load 'myupdate' from server 'foo'
driverupdate=ftp://foo/myupdate
# search & load 'update1' on local disks and load update2 from network
driverupdate=disk:/update1 driverupdate=http://foo/update2

   For easy testing the semantics has been extended a bit: if <url> does
   not point to a driverupdate but rather a normal file system image, cpio
   archive, or rpm, it is unpacked and the files are added to the install
   (or rescue) system. (But note that this currently works only with ftp
   and http urls.)

   Examples:
# add ftp server to rescue system
# rescue=1 dud=http://foo/bar/vsftpd.rpm

   DUD

   Alias for [62]driverupdate parameter.
   ESCDelay

   ethtool

   Run [63]ethtool for any or all network interfaces. Ethtool can change
   ethernet card settings. See man ethtool for details.

   Format:
[if0=]option

   Examples:
"ethtool=eth0=duplex full"     # only applies to eth0
"ethtool=speed 10"             # applies to all network interfaces

   Exec

   Executes an additional binary.

   Example:
exec=/usr/bin/top

   Expert

   deprecated

   Combines Textmode and DriverUpdate
 Values:
 0 ignored
 1 enable text mode
 2 ask for driver update disk
 3 both

   FloppyDevice

   No longer supported. Use [64]install.
   ForceRootimage

   No longer supported.
   Gateway

   This specifies the gateway through which the installation server can be
   reached if it is not located in the subnetwork of the host.

   Example:
gateway=192.168.1.1

   HasPCMCIA

   HostIP

   Specifies the static IP address of the host. The number of network bits
   can be appended, saving you the extra netmask parameter.

   Examples:
hostip=192.168.1.101
# or, giving netmask 255.255.255.0 as well
hostip=192.168.1.101/24

   Hostname

   Full qualified hostname.
   HWDetect

   Controls hardware detection.
 Values: 0 (off), 1 (on)

   Info

   Specifies the file to read more options from as URL. For supported
   schemes and a syntax description, look [65]here.

   linuxrc reads all specified files. A file may contain further info
   parameters.

   Examples:
info=cd:/info1
info=disk:/install/info2
info=http://foo/bar/info3

   InitrdID

   Forces initrd ID to a given value. linuxrc compares instsys and initrd
   IDs and only proceeds if both are identical.
   InitrdModules

   List of additional modules to put into the installed system's initrd.
   Insecure

   linuxrc checks SHA1 sums of all files it downloads. They are taken from
   (repository):/content after its signature has been verified.

   If you don't want this, do:
insecure=1

   Note that it is not possible to bring linuxrc back into secure mode
   after this. In particular:
insecure=0

   will not work.
   Insmod

   This specifies a module the kernel should load, together with any
   parameters needed for it. Module parameters must be separated by
   blanks.

   The module is loaded before hardware detection starts. Module
   dependencies are automatically resolved (the name insmod is a bit
   misleading here).

   Note that modules blacklisted with [66]brokenmodules cannot be loaded
   this way.

   Examples:
# load ahci
insmod=ahci
# remember the quotes
insmod="loop max_loop=100"
# load several modules
insmod=tg3 insmod=e1000

   Install

   Specifies the installation repository as URL. For supported schemes and
   a syntax description, look [67]here.

   It must point to either a directory or an ISO image.

   Additionally, a special scheme exec is supported which does not need a
   repository but just runs the argument after linuxrc did the hardware
   setup.

   Examples:
# from CD-ROM
install=cd:/
# ftp from server foo, directory openSUSE-10.3-i386
install=ftp://foo/pub/openSUSE-10.3-i386
# local disk, ISO image openSUSE-10.3-i386-DVD.iso
install=hd://install/openSUSE-10.3-i386-DVD.iso
# Windows share bar, ISO image openSUSE-10.3-i386-DVD.iso
install=smb://foo/bar/openSUSE-10.3-i386-DVD.iso
# get real URL via SLP
install=slp:/
# just start a shell
install=exec:/bin/sh

   The installation program is normally loaded from the repository. If for
   some reason you don't want this, you can specify the installation
   system image to use explicitly by adding ?instsys= or using the
   [68]instsys parameter; for example:
install=cd:/?instsys=ftp://testserver/foo
# is the same as
instsys=ftp://testserver/foo install=cd:/

   InstallDir

   No longer supported. Use [69]install.
   InstMode

   No longer supported. Use [70]install.
   Instsys

   Specifies the installation system to use. Default value is
   boot/<arch>/root. May point to a file system image or to a directory.
   For supported schemes and a syntax description, look [71]here. See
   [72]install for an alternative way to specify it.

   Example:
instsys=my/zappel          # use my/zappel from repository
instsys=http://foo/zappel  # use zappel from server foo

   InstsysComplain

   Controls what initrd should do if initrd ID and instsys ID do not
   match.
 Values:
 0 ignore
 1 print a warning
 2 abort with an error

   In non-Beta systems this parameter defaults to 0 (ignore).
   InstsysID

   Force instsys ID to a given value. linuxrc compares instsys and initrd
   IDs and only proceeds if both are identical.
   ipv4

   [openSUSE 11.1+]

   Turn on IPv4 support. (This is the default.)
   ipv4only

   [openSUSE 11.1+]

   Turn on IPv4 support, disable IPv6.

   Example:
 ipv4only=1
 # is identical to
 ipv6only=0

   ipv6

   [experimental]

   Turn on IPv6 support (additionally to IPv4).
   ipv6only

   [experimental]

   Turn on IPv6 support, disable IPv4.

   Example:
 ipv6only=1

   KBDTimeout

   windowed only

   Keyboard timeout in seconds. The time after which linuxrc proceeds with
   default values if no input is made. Default to 0 (off).
   Kexec

   If set to 1, linuxrc will load kernel and initrd from the repository
   and restart with them.

   Spares people installing via network the download of the Boot-CD as you
   can keep using an old one.

   Available only for x86 and x86-64 currently.

   Example:
 kexec=1

   kexec_reboot

   If set to 1 (the default on most machines), then kexec will be used to
   reboot the machine after finishing the 1st stage of installation. If
   set to 0, a normal reboot will be used. There is some blacklist
   maintained in YaST (for example for VirtualBox) for machine that are
   known to be broken with kexec.

   Keytable

   Virtual console keyboard map to load.
 Example:
 Keytable=fr-latin1

   Lang

   Alias for Language parameter.
   Language

   Language preselected for the installation.
 Example:
 Language=de_DE
 Language=fr_FR
 Language=cs_CZ

   Linemode

   Enables line-mode usable on dumb terminals.

   Example:
 linemode=1

   linuxrc

   Obsolete. Please don't use.
   LinuxrcDebug

   Comma-separated list of a numerical debug level (max. 4) and debug
   flags. Flags can be turned on or off (prepend '+' or '-'). Debug flags
   currently supported are:
     * tmpfs: move everything into tmpfs at start-up (default)
     * udev: use udev to manage /dev tree (default)
     * udev.mods: let udev load modules (default)
     * wait: stop at critical points and wait for a keypress

   Examples:
# a reasonable amount of debug info
linuxrc.debug=1
# ... and stop at some critical points
linuxrc.debug=1,wait
# linuxrc loads drivers itself
linuxrc.debug=-udev.mods
# don't copy files into tmpfs (but keep them in ramfs)
linuxrc.debug=-tmpfs

   LinuxrcLog

   Device to print log messages to. Defaults to /dev/tty3. To see more log
   messages, increase the [73]debug level.

   Example:
# save all log messages to 'foo'
linuxrc.log=/foo
# show them on the default console (ideally together with [74]linemode)
linuxrc.log=/dev/console linemode=1

   LinuxrcSTDERR

   Obsolete. Use [75]linuxrclog.
   Listen

   * experimental *

   linuxrc sets up the network and listens on the specified port for
   input. (You may want to use [76]manual=1 along with this option and
   then connect via telnet to linuxrc.)

   Examples:
# wait for input on port 1234
listen=1234

   Loghost

   Hostname to redirect syslog to. Also YaST will log both to y2log and to
   the remote syslog.

   To enable log reception on the destination host, see "source" section
   in /etc/syslog-ng/syslog-ng.conf
   LogLevel

   Set kernel log level.
 Values: 1 - 8

   Defaults to 1 for serial consoles, 7 for all other consoles.
   LXRCDebug

   Obsolete. Use [77]linuxrcdebug.
   Manual

   Start linuxrc in manual mode.
 Values:
 0 automatic mode (this is the default)
 1 manual mode
 2 really manual manual mode (E.g. no USB keyboard since no USB setup is done!)

   There's normally no reason to use manual mode. Please avoid it. You can
   pass everything directly via command line.

   manual=1 still uses hardware detection to some degree (e.g. to mark
   suitable modules in module loading dialogs) but you basically have to
   take care to load all necessary drivers yourself.

   manual=2 does no automatic hardware detection at all and is useful only
   if the hardware detection has some problem. A typical example would be
   linuxrc not letting you select a network interface even though the
   driver is loaded and the interface exists.
   MemLimit

   Amount of free memory in kB below which linuxrc will ask the user to
   set up a swap partition.
   MemLoadImage

   Amount of free memory in kB below which linuxrc will not copy the root
   image into RAM.
   MemYaST

   Amount of free memory in kB below which linuxrc will start YaST in text
   mode.
   MemYaSTText

   Amount of free memory in kB below which linuxrc will ask the user to
   set up a swap partition before starting YaST.
   MinMemory

   Amount of memory in kB below which linuxrc will refuse to start.
   Defaults to 0.
   ModuleDelay

   Wait some seconds after loading each module. Useful if your hardware is
   a bit slow.
 Example:
 # wait 5 seconds
 ModuleDelay=5

   Defaults to 0.
   ModuleDisks

   No longer supported.
   NameScheme

   [openSUSE 11.3+]

   Selects the device name scheme linuxrc uses. Value can be by-id,
   by-path, by-label or "".

   Default setting is by-id

   Examples:
# back to classical device names (like /dev/sda)
namescheme=
# use /dev/disk/by-path/...
namescheme=by-path

   Nameserver

   Comma-separated list of DNS servers.

   Examples:
# just one
Nameserver=192.168.1.1
# or more
Nameserver=192.168.1.2,192.168.1.3

   Netdevice

   Specify the network interface. See [78]device description for allowed
   values.

   Normally, this is not necessary. But if you really need this option,
   consider adding it to the URL of the [79]Install parameter.

   Examples:
netdevice=eth1        # 2nd ethernet interface
netdevice=wlan*       # wlan interface

   Netmask

   also via DHCP

   Static IP netmask of the installing host.
   Netretry

   Netretry=N will retry all network connection attempts N times (e.g.,
   when trying to reach the FTP server). This is mainly for debugging
   network problems.
   NetSetup

   Prompt for network parameters and setup network. Normally linuxrc will
   do this automatically when you [80]install via network. But if you want
   to configure the network even if you install from local media, use this
   option.

   netsetup accepts a comma-separated list of default, dhcp, hostip,
   netmask, gateway, nameserver, now, or all.

   Flags can be turned on or off (prepend '+' or '-').

   Examples:
# default = dhcp,hostip,netmask,gateway,nameserver
netsetup=default
# same as 'default'
netsetup=1
# do dhcp
netsetup=dhcp
# setup all interfaces
netsetup=dhcp,all
# ask for static network parameters and configure it immediately
netsetup=-dhcp,now


   _NetStop

   internal
   NetUniqueID
   NetWait

   Wait some seconds after activating the network interface. This might be
   needed in rare cases for some cards.

   If you have problems with DHCP, also look at [81]dhcpcd; for BOOTP, try
   [82]bootpwait
 Example:
 # wait 8 seconds
 NetWait=8

   Network

   also via DHCP
   NewID
   NFSOpts

   NFS mount options. A comma-separated list. Supported options are vers,
   tcp, udp, rsize and wsize.

   Examples:
# use NFSv2 via UDP
nfsopts=udp,vers=2
# different block size
nfsopts=rsize=4096,wsize=4096

   NFS.RSize

   Obsolete. Use [83]NFSOpts.
   NFS.TCP

   No longer supported. Use [84]NFSOpts.
   NFS.WSize

   Obsolete. Use [85]NFSOpts.
   NoMDNS

   Turn off MDNS usage.

   Example:
nomdns=1

   NoPCMCIA

   deprecated

   Do not start the PCMCIA card manager. This option may not be useful any
   more.
   NoShell

   Do not start any shell. By default, linuxrc starts /bin/bash at
   /dev/tty2, /dev/tty9 and if memory requirements permit (well, about
   always) also at /dev/tty5 and /dev/tty6.

   See also parameters MemLimit, MemYaST and MemYaSTText.
 Example:
 noshell=1

   Options

   Pass options to kernel modules. Syntax is "module.parameter" or
   "module=parameter".

   Examples:
# "tzp=50" for module "thermal"
options=thermal.tzp=50
# looks a bit weird, but means the same:
options=thermal=tzp=50
# create 100 loop devices
options=loop.max_loop=100

   Alternatively, all options that are unknown but have the form foo.bar
   are interpreted as option bar to module foo.

   Examples:
thermal.tzp=50
loop.max_loop=100

   To pass several options to a module, use, e.g.:
libata.atapi_enabled=1 libata.ignore_hpa=1
# same as above, but in one go:
options="libata.atapi_enabled=1 ignore_hpa=1"

   Partition

   No longer supported. Use [86]device or [87]install.
   Password

   No longer supported. Use [88]install.
   PCMCIA
   Product
   ProductDir
   Proxy

   Defines a HTTP proxy server. For a URL syntax overview, look [89]here.

   Examples:
# use proxy.foo.org on port 3128
proxy=http://proxy.foo.org:3128
# using 'http://' is optional:
proxy=proxy.foo.org:3128
# or, with authentication
proxy=http://foo:bar@proxy.foo.org:3128

   ProxyPort

   No longer supported. Use [90]proxy.
   ProxyProto

   No longer supported. Use [91]proxy.
   Rescue

   Load the rescue system. See [92]install for syntax.

   Alternatively, use rescue=1 and [93]install or [94]instsys.
   RescueImage

   Location of the rescue system image within the installation source.
   RootImage

   Location of root image (installation system image) within the
   installation source.
   RootImage2

   No longer supported.
   RootPassword

   Linuxrc asks for a root's password.
 Example:
 RootPassword=ask

   RootPath

   DHCP only
   Sax2

   Use sax2 to setup Xorg (graphics) during installation. This might be
   useful if you have some unusual hardware. Or you are in a virtual
   machine.

   Example:
sax2=1

   Screenmap

   Obsolete, do not use (it does not do what you probably think [if you
   think of anything it could do ;) ]).
   SCSIBeforeUSB
   SCSIRename
   Server
   Serverdir

   No longer supported. Use [95]install.
   SetupCmd
   SetupNetIF
   Share

   No longer supported. Use [96]install.
   Splash

   Defines whether a splash-screen is used during initialization.
 Example
 Splash=silent
 Splash=verbose

   SSH

   This parameter enables access to linuxrc via SSH when performing the
   installation with YaST in text mode or via X11 forwarding. Use ssh -X
   root@hostname or ssh -Y root@hostname for X11 forwarding.
 Values: 0 (off), 1 (on)

   Example:
 # use ssh and set ssh password
 ssh=1 sshpassword=foobar123

   SSHPassword

   This sets the password for the user root for logging into the SSH
   server during installation if UseSSH is set. This is not the password
   of the system to be installed. See RootPassword.

   Example:
 SSHPassword=12345678

   StartShell

   Boots into the installation system and starts a shell. Waits until user
   exits the shell. User can modify the installation system, mount or
   remount partitions or start YaST installation manually by running yast.

   Example:
 StartShell=1

   StaticDevices
   TERM

   Terminal type on which linuxrc is running
 Example:
 TERM=dumb

   _TestMode

   internal config file only
   Textmode

   Enables starting YaST in text mode otherwise it starts in Qt if
   possible.
 Example:
 Textmode=1

   TFTPTimeout

   Timeout for TFTP connections in seconds.
   _TmpFS

   No longer supported.
   UdevRule

   Write udev rules. Currently only writing network rules to
   70-persistent-net.rules is implemented. If the need arises, more can
   follow.

   Note that this option is only useful on command line or in
   linuxrc.config as the rules need to be written before udevd is started
   (which is rather early).

   Example:
 # add entry to 70-persistent-net.rules
 udev.rule="mac=00:11:d8:39:4e:d0,name=eth0"

   UpdateComplain
   UpdateDir
   UpdateExpected
   UpdateID

   config file only
   UpdateName
   UpdatePriority

   config file only
   UpdateStyle
   USBWait

   Number of seconds to wait after loading USB modules.
   UseDHCP

   If an automatic network setup is required, defines whether DHCP or
   BOOTP should be used. Default is DHCP.
 Example:
 # use BOOTP
 UseDHCP=0

   Username

   No longer supported. Use [97]install.
   UseSax2

   Alias for [98]sax2 parameter.
   SSH

   This parameter enables access to linuxrc via SSH when performing the
   installation with YaST in text mode or via X11 forwarding. Use ssh -X
   root@hostname or ssh -Y root@hostname for X11 forwarding.
 Values: 0 (off), 1 (on)

   Example:
 # use ssh and set ssh password
 ssh=1 sshpassword=foobar123

   UseSSH

   Alias for [99]ssh parameter.
   UseVNC

   Alias for [100]vnc parameter.
   VNC

   The VNC parameter enables the installation process via VNC, making the
   installation more convenient on hosts that have no or no really usable
   local console. If enabled, a VNC server is activated on the
   installation host. See also VNCPassword.

   Example:
vnc=1 # enable VNC

   VNCPassword

   This sets the VNC password for an installation via VNC.
 Example:
 VNCPassword=12345678

   WaitReboot
   WithiSCSI

   During installation starts [101]YaST module to configure iSCSI
   initiator
   WlanAuth
   WlanESSID
   WlanKeyAscii
   WlanKeyHex
   WlanKeyLen
   WlanKeyPass
   WorkDomain

   No longer supported. Use [102]install.
   YaST2update
   YaST2color
   Zen

   No longer supported.
   ZenConfig

   No longer supported.
   Zombies

   If you don't want linuxrc to take care of zombie processes during
   installation, set this to 0. (Don't do this.)

   Example:
zombies=0

Special parameters for S/390 and zSeries

    Parameter   Description
   CTCProtocol

   CTC protocol to use.
 Values:
 0 compatible
 1 extended
 2 z/OS

   DataChannel

   CCW data channel for CU3088 and QDIO devices
 Format: h.h.hhhh

   InstNetDev

   Network device to install from.
 Values:
 osa OSA-2 or OSA Express
 hsi Hipersocket
 ctc CTC (deprecated)
 escon ESCON (deprecated)
 iucv IUCV (deprecated)

   IUCVPeer

   Name of peer for IUCV networking.
   Layer2

   Turn on OSI layer 2 access for OSA Express Ethernet interfaces.
 Values: 0 (off), 1 (on)

   OSAHWAddr

   introduced in SLE10 SP1
   Manual MAC address setting for Layer 2-enabled OSA devices. Note that
   this is distinct from HWAddr, which contains the default MAC address as
   detected by linuxrc.
 Example: OSAHWAddr=11:22:33:44:55:66

   OSAInterface

   Software interface for OSA devices.
 Values:
 qdio QDIO
 lcs LCS

   OSAMedium

   Physical medium for OSA devices.
 Values:
 eth Ethernet
 tr Token Ring

   Portname

   Portname for OSA devices.
   ReadChannel

   CCW read channel for CU3088 and QDIO devices.
 Format: h.h.hhhh

   WriteChannel

   CCW write channel for CU3088 and QDIO devices.
 Format: h.h.hhhh

Special parameters not handled by Linuxrc itself

    Parameter   Description
   Mem

   Defines a maximum RAM that will be used by the installation system.
   It's helpful for testing installation memory requirements.
 Example:
 mem=128M

   Y2_BRAILLE

   This environment variable sets the style of installation textmode UI to
   'braille' i.e. it is optimized for visually impaired people. Use
   together with 'textmode=1'
 Example:
 Y2_BRAILLE=1

   Y2DEBUG

   Turns all YaST debugging messages on. These messages are logged into
   the /var/log/YaST2/y2log file marked with <0> flag. This parameter is
   handled by [103]YaST itself and can be also prepended to the
   command line when starting any YaST module.
   TERM

   Setting this environment variable influences the color style that will
   be used in installation textmode UI. E.g. TERM=xterm sets the theme to
   xterm, some TERM not supporting colors will use monochromatic theme.
   When not set, default theme linux is applied. However, be careful and
   before setting any TERM value, check that it has valid terminfo entry.
   Otherwise installation may abort.

   Available terms can be found in the
   /yast/instsource/inst-sys/usr/share/terminfo directory - installation
   system has another set of available terms than a running system. To get
   a monochromatic term, use linux-m.

   Use this parameter together with textmode=1.
 Example:
 TERM=xterm
 TERM=linux-m

   ZYPP_FULLLOG

   Sets [104]LibZYPP logging level to the highest value. Useful for
   debugging products, packages and patches dependency problems. This
   variable can be also set on a running system before running every
   [105]YaST module.
 Example:
 ZYPP_FULLLOG=1                           # Linuxrc
 ZYPP_FULLLOG=1 /sbin/yast2 online_update # Running system

Errata

openSUSE 10.3

     * [106]info=file:/file_name does not work if file_name is 'info';
       just use another name

     * [107]netwait does not apply to DHCP

     * [108]rescue=url is not sufficient; use '[109]rescue=1
       [110]rescue=url'

     * [111]instsys=url does not setup network if the ftp or http schemes
       are used and [112]install does not refer to a network url. Use the
       [113]netsetup option as a workaround.

   Retrieved from "[114]http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc"
   [115]Categories: [116]Booting | [117]Installation | [118]YaST
   The content on this and other wiki pages is posted by community members
   who are not acting for or on behalf of Novell, Inc., whether
   they otherwise have affiliation with Novell.
   This site uses the [119]YAML CSS framework.
   [120]About openSUSE | [121]Disclaimers | [122]Feedback
   This page was last modified on 26 February 2010, at 16:16. This page
   has been accessed 46,232 times.
   [123]Founded by Novell

References

   1. http://en.opensuse.org/opensearch_desc.php
   2. http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=Special:RecentChanges&feed=rss
   3. http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=Special:RecentChanges&feed=atom
   4. http://en.opensuse.org/Welcome%20to%20openSUSE.org
   5. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#top
   6. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#searchbox
   7. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#firstnavitem
   8. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p-tb
   9. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#page_actions
  10. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p-lang
  11. http://en.opensuse.org/
  12. http://software.opensuse.org/
  13. http://en.opensuse.org/
  14. http://build.opensuse.org/
  15. http://users.opensuse.org/
  16. https://features.opensuse.org/
  17. http://news.opensuse.org/
  18. http://forums.opensuse.org/
  19. http://shop.opensuse.org/
  20. http://en.opensuse.org/Project_Overview
  21. http://en.opensuse.org/How_to_Participate
  22. http://en.opensuse.org/Documentation
  23. http://en.opensuse.org/Support
  24. http://en.opensuse.org/SDB:SDB
  25. http://en.opensuse.org/Contact
  26. http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Browse
  27. http://en.opensuse.org/Special:WhatLinksHere/Linuxrc
  28. http://en.opensuse.org/Special:RecentChangesLinked/Linuxrc
  29. http://en.opensuse.org/Special:SpecialPages
  30. http://nl.opensuse.org/Linuxrc
  31. http://de.opensuse.org/Linuxrc
  32. http://ja.opensuse.org/Linuxrc
  33. http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=Special:UserLogin&returnto=Linuxrc
  34. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc
  35. http://en.opensuse.org/Talk:Linuxrc
  36. http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=Linuxrc&action=edit
  37. http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=Linuxrc&action=history
  38. http://en.opensuse.org/YaST
  39. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  40. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc/install.inf
  41. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc/install.inf
  42. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#Passing_parameters
  43. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#Parameter_Reference
  44. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#Special_parameters_for_S.2F390_and_zSeries
  45. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#Special_parameters_not_handled_by_Linuxrc_itself
  46. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#Errata
  47. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#openSUSE_10.3
  48. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_info
  49. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_options
  50. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  51. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_instsys
  52. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  53. http://en.opensuse.org/Autoyast_installation_using_a_network_installation_source
  54. ftp://autoyast_profile.xml/
  55. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_device
  56. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  57. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#device_descr
  58. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  59. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_dud
  60. http://ftp.suse.com/pub/people/hvogel/Update-Media-HOWTO/index.html
  61. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#url_descr
  62. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_driverupdate
  63. http://en.opensuse.org/index.php?title=Ethtool&action=edit&redlink=1
  64. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  65. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#url_descr
  66. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_brokenmodules
  67. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#url_descr
  68. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_instsys
  69. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  70. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  71. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#url_descr
  72. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  73. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_linuxrcdebug
  74. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_linemode
  75. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_linuxrclog
  76. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_manual
  77. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_linuxrcdebug
  78. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#device_descr
  79. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  80. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  81. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_dhcpcd
  82. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_bootpwait
  83. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_nfsopts
  84. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_nfsopts
  85. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_nfsopts
  86. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_device
  87. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  88. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  89. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#url_descr
  90. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_proxy
  91. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_proxy
  92. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  93. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  94. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_instsys
  95. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  96. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  97. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
  98. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_sax2
  99. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_ssh
 100. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_vnc
 101. http://en.opensuse.org/YaST
 102. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
 103. http://en.opensuse.org/YaST
 104. http://en.opensuse.org/Libzypp/Main_page
 105. http://en.opensuse.org/YaST
 106. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_info
 107. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_netwait
 108. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_rescue
 109. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_rescue
 110. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_rescue
 111. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_instsys
 112. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_install
 113. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc#p_netsetup
 114. http://en.opensuse.org/Linuxrc
 115. http://en.opensuse.org/Special:Categories
 116. http://en.opensuse.org/Category:Booting
 117. http://en.opensuse.org/Category:Installation
 118. http://en.opensuse.org/Category:YaST
 119. http://www.yaml.de/
 120. http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:About
 121. http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:General_disclaimer
 122. mailto:webmaster@opensuse.org
 123. http://www.novell.com/linux/


 -->
</chapter>
