<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//Novell//DTD NovDoc XML V1.0//EN" "novdocx.dtd"
[
  <!ENTITY % NOVDOC.DEACTIVATE.IDREF "INCLUDE">
  <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
  %entities;
  ]>
<!--taroth 090302: basket is not on the media - drop this chapter for  next release?-->
<!--toms 2011-08-08: Not available in SLED11 SP2, removing -->
<chapter id="cha.basket">
 <title>Taking Notes with BasKet</title>
 <para>
  BasKet is a note-taking application that allows you to collect and sort
  all kind of data. It helps with writing down your ideas, making to do
  lists, and allocating your contacts. You can sort the data in hierarchies
  and share it with other people. If needed, you can even protect some of
  your baskets with passwords.
 </para>
 <sect1 id="cha.basket.creatingBaskets">
  <title>Creating Baskets</title>

  <para>
   A basket is a document in which you can place notes. Create baskets that
   include different topics, contents, or projects and give each its own
   layout.
  </para>

  <procedure>
   <step>
    <para>
     To start <phrase role="productname">BasKet</phrase>, open a shell with
     <keycombo> <keycap function="alt"></keycap> <keycap>F2</keycap>
     </keycombo> and enter <command>basket</command>.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     To create a basket, select <menuchoice> <guimenu>Basket</guimenu>
     <guimenu>New</guimenu> <guimenu>New Basket</guimenu></menuchoice>.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     Enter a name for your basket and select a template for its column
     structure.
    </para>
   </step>
   <step>
    <para>
     The basket tree on the left side shows all your baskets.
    </para>
    <para>
     Right-click a basket in the tree and select <menuchoice>
     <guimenu>Properties</guimenu> </menuchoice> to give it a special
     appearance (background color or image and text color), change its
     disposition (column format), or create a shortcut for it.
    </para>
   </step>
  </procedure>

  <figure id="fig.basketOverview">
   <title>Basket in Use</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject role="fo">
     <imagedata fileref="basket_overview.png" width="70%"/>
    </imageobject>
    <imageobject role="html">
     <imagedata fileref="basket_overview.png" width="70%"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <note>
   <title>Saving your Baskets</title>
   <para>
    There is no need to save your work. It is saved automatically.
   </para>
  </note>

  <para>
   To assure a clearly arranged structure, you may want to create sibling
   baskets or sub-baskets as well. You can do this by selecting <menuchoice>
   <guimenu>Basket</guimenu> <guimenu>New</guimenu> <guimenu>New
   Sub-Basket</guimenu></menuchoice>. The sub-basket appears one level down
   the parent basket. By selecting <menuchoice> <guimenu>Basket</guimenu>
   <guimenu>New</guimenu> <guimenu>New Sibling-Basket</guimenu></menuchoice>
   you create a basket in the same level as the parent basket. In both cases
   the new baskets inherit the appearance and disposition from their parent
   baskets.
  </para>
 </sect1>
 <sect1 id="cha.basket.workingBaskets">
  <title>Working with Baskets</title>

  <para>
   After creating your baskets and sub-baskets, fill them with different
   notes. Notes can include different types of data, for example text,
   images, URLs, application launchers as well as links, e-mail addresses,
   files and colors.
  </para>

  <sect2>
   <title>Filling and Personalizing your Baskets</title>
   <para>
    To insert notes into baskets, just right-click the area on the right
    side and choose the type of data you need to add. You can import screen
    shots or colors picked from the screen into your baskets. For a screen
    shot, select <menuchoice> <guimenu>Insert</guimenu> <guimenu>Grab from
    screen</guimenu></menuchoice>. To select a screen color, use
    <menuchoice> <guimenu>Insert</guimenu> <guimenu>Color from
    Screen</guimenu></menuchoice>.
   </para>
   <para>
    You may want to assign tags to your notes to structure them. Tags are
    marks that represent the priority, preference, or progress of a note.
    Select <menuchoice> <guimenu>Tags</guimenu> </menuchoice> and simply
    check or uncheck the tags to assign or remove them from the selected
    notes. Customize the available tags by selecting <menuchoice>
    <guimenu>Tags</guimenu> <guimenu>Customize</guimenu> </menuchoice>.
   </para>
   <figure id="fig.basketCustomizingTags">
    <title>Customizing Tags</title>
    <mediaobject>
     <imageobject role="fo">
      <imagedata fileref="basket_customizeTags.png" width="95%"/>
     </imageobject>
     <imageobject role="html">
      <imagedata fileref="basket_customizeTags.png" width="95%"/>
     </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
   </figure>
   <para>
    To group notes that belong together select the ones you want to group,
    right-click them and select <guimenu>Group</guimenu>. To break up a
    group of notes, make sure you selected the whole group of notes, then
    right-click and select <guimenu>Ungroup</guimenu>.
   </para>
   <para>
    You can move a note within a group of notes by selecting <menuchoice>
    <guimenu>Note</guimenu> <guimenu>Move Up</guimenu> </menuchoice>. If you
    want to move a note from within a group of notes outside it, select
    <menuchoice> <guimenu>Note</guimenu> <guimenu>Move On Top</guimenu>
    </menuchoice>.
   </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2>
   <title>Importing and Exporting Baskets</title>
   <para>
    If you worked with other note-taking applications in the past and do not
    want to lose the collected information, import these files to BasKet.
    You can import data from the applications KNotes, KJots, and
    StickyNotes. To do that, right-click either in the tree structure on the
    left side or directly on the basket into which you want to import the
    notes and select <guimenu>Import</guimenu>.
   </para>
   <remark condition="clarity">
    2007-07-16 - jjaeger: what about other apps like Tomboy and tuxcards?
    Review for next release!
    </remark>
   <para>
    After collecting and sorting a lot of data, you might want to share it
    with other people. There are two ways to prepare your notes for sharing:
   </para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>
      Export a basket into HTML files by right-clicking the basket you want
      to export and selecting <menuchoice> <guimenu>Export</guimenu>
      <guimenu>HTML Web Page</guimenu></menuchoice>.
     </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>
      For others to be able to open and modify your baskets, export them
      into basket archives. Right-click the basket you want to export and
      select <menuchoice> <guimenu>Export</guimenu> <guimenu>Basket
      Archive</guimenu></menuchoice>.
     </para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <remark condition="clarity">
    2007-07-16 - jjaeger: todo for next release ... HOW does a user work with
    those shared basket archives?
    </remark>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="sec.basket.workingBaskets.protectingBaskets">
   <title>Protecting Baskets</title>
   <para>
    There might be baskets that you want to protect with a password so you
    are the only person who can access them. To protect a basket using a
    password or private and public keys Right-click the basket and select
    <guimenu>Password</guimenu>.
   </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2>
   <title>Finding Data</title>
   <para>
    Once you have several baskets, finding specific data can be challenging.
    You have different possibilities to find the information you are looking
    for very quickly even without remembering its exact title:
   </para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>
      Find notes by simply typing a word or two in the filter box.
     </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>
      If you are searching for notes with a certain tag assigned to them,
      select the desired tag in the tag box.
     </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>
      The icon on the right applies a filter to every basket.
     </para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <para>
    The numbers in the basket tree on the left indicate how many notes match
    your search options. The lock icon indicates that the basket is
    currently locked, so has not been searched. For more information, see
    <xref
       linkend="sec.basket.workingBaskets.protectingBaskets"/>.
   </para>
  </sect2>

  <sect2 id="sec.basket.backup">
   <title>Creating and Restoring Backups</title>
   <para>
    Basket can backup your data for you. Select <menuchoice>
    <guimenu>Basket</guimenu> <guimenu>Backup &amp; Restore...</guimenu>
    </menuchoice> to open a dialog box. It shows you where your baskets are
    stored in. You can select a different folder when you select the buttons
    <guimenu>Move to Another Folder...</guimenu> or <guimenu>Use Another
    Existing Folder...</guimenu>, depending on your need. Start the backup
    process with <guimenu>Backup...</guimenu> and give your archive a name.
    A previously backup can be restored with <guimenu>Restore a
    Backup...</guimenu> and select the respective archive.
   </para>
  </sect2>
 </sect1>
 <sect1>
  <title>For More Information</title>

  <para>
   The official home page of BasKet is
   <ulink
    url="http://basket.kde.org/index.php"></ulink>. This site
   offers a tour through the application, news of the latest versions, and a
   collection of screen shots showing different use cases.
  </para>
 </sect1>
</chapter>
