<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="urn:x-suse:xslt:profiling:docbook51-profile.xsl"
    type="text/xml"
    title="Profiling step"
?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter
[
   <!ENTITY % entities SYSTEM "entity-decl.ent">
   %entities;
]>


<!--
  
  toms 2012-03-18:
  
  * FATE#313910
  * Users Guide:
    http://tipc.sourceforge.net/doc/tipc_2.0_users_guide.html
  * Programmers Guide:
    http://tipc.sourceforge.net/doc/tipc_2.0_prog_guide.html

-->
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1" xml:id="cha-tuning-tipc"><title>Transparent Inter-Process Communication (TIPC)</title><info/>
  
  <para><emphasis>Transparent Inter-Process Communication</emphasis>
    is a non-IP based network communication protocol specially designed for networks
    in a cluster environment.
  </para>
  
  <section xml:id="sec-tuning-tipc-overview">
    <title>Conceptual Overview</title>
    <para>Based on some empirical knowledge about cluster environments,
      the protocol operations match the following assumptions:</para>
    <itemizedlist mark="bullet" spacing="normal">
      <listitem>
        <para>Most messages cross only one direct hop and have a
          relative short transfer time.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Highly available bandwidth and memory volume</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The number of inter-communicating nodes is relatively
          static and limited at any moment in time.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Security is a less crucial issue in closed clusters than
          on the Internet.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    
    <para>Conceptually, the TIPC topology need not be the same than the
      topology of your network. Actually it can be totally different.
      Usually, a TIPC computer is called a
        <emphasis>node</emphasis>. A set of related nodes form a
        <emphasis>cluster</emphasis>, while a set of related clusters
      form a <emphasis>zone</emphasis>. 
      Typically, the grouping is based on location. For example, a
      cluster contains all nodes which are in the same rack or in the
      same room, while a zone contains all clusters in the same
      building.
    </para>
    <para>Each node in a TIPC network is assigned a unique network
      address. This TIPC address consists of a zone (Z), cluster (C), 
      and a node identifier (N) in the form
      <literal>&lt;Z.C.N&gt;</literal>. 
      Each of these identifiers is an integer value. By default, the
      maximum values for a zone, cluster, and node identifiers are 3, 1,
      and 63. Theoretically, it can reach 255 (Z), 4095 (C), and 2047
      (N), respectively. Usually, it is definied by the network
      administrator.
    </para>
    <para>The TIPC network address is not the same as the IP network
      address. 
      There is only one network address per node in TIPC, even if the 
      node has multiple network interfaces.  A node's network interfaces 
      are <emphasis>not</emphasis> assigned network addresses at all.</para>
  </section>
  
  <section xml:id="sec-tuning-tipc-config">
    <title>Configuring TIPC Nodes</title>
    <para>Once you have think about the overview of your network, before
    you work with TIPC, enable the Kernel module first:</para>
    <screen>modprobe tipc</screen>
    <para>After the module is successfully loaded, define the address
      (<option>--addr</option>), the network device
      (<option>-be</option>):</para>
    <screen>tipc-config <!---netid=1234--> --addr=1.1.8 -be=eth:eth0</screen>
    <para>Once the TIPC address is set it cannot be changed anymore!</para>
  </section>
  
</chapter>
